Finding Aid for the Norman Cousins Papers LSC.1385
UCLA Library Special Collections
Norman Cousins papers
1924-1991
1944-1990
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.1385
908.0 Linear Feet (1816 boxes)
1816 boxes (908 linear ft.)
Box 1558-1660
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Norman Cousins, 1984-1987.
Gift of Mrs. Ellen Cousins, 1991.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 999645463606533
Biography
Cousins was born on June 24, 1915 in Union Hill, New Jersey; attended Teachers College, Columbia University; began working at New York post as the education editor, 1934-35; worked at Current history as book reviewer, literary editor, and managing editor, 1935-40; married Eleanor (Ellen) Kopf in 1939; executive editor (1940-42), and editor-in-chief (1942-71) of Saturday Review Of Literature, later known as Saturday Review; editor of World (1972-73), Saturday Review/World (1973-74), and Saturday Review (1975-78); worked on editorial board of Office of War Information during World War II; he was involved with organizations fostering world government and control of nuclear weapons, serving as president of United World Federalists from 1952-54 and as founding member of the Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy (SANE); founded US-USSR and US-Chinese Writers Conferences; served as a diplomat during 3 presidential administrations; produced numerous books on political, social, and medical issues; adjunct professor of medical humanities, UCLA, beginning in 1978, where he initiated the Task Force in Psychoneuroimmunology; received many awards, including the United Nations Peace Medal, the Albert Schweitzer Prize of Humanitarianism, and nearly fifty honorary doctorate degrees; he died on Nov. 30, 1990 in Los Angeles, CA.
Scope and Content
Collection covers the range of Cousins' career as magazine editor, author, and professor, with particular concentration in the subject areas of world government and medical issues, mostly concerning the role of the mind in healing the body. It consists of correspondence, subject files, photographs, scrapbooks, videotapes, audio tapes, datebooks and calendars, telephone logs, posters, and drafts of editorials, articles, speeches, radio broadcasts, and books.
Organization and Arrangement
Summary
1. Material of the Office of War Information
······Document Cases 1-14
2. Project X
······Document Cases 15-43
3. UWF
······Document Cases 44-59
4. Personal and Business Correspondence
······Document Cases 60-107
5. Printed Material
······Document Cases 108-128
6. Personal and Business Correspondence
······Document Cases 120-180
7. Personal and Business Correspondence
······Document Cases 180-299
8. Personal and Business Correspondence
······Document Cases 300-329
9. Miscellaneous (Trips, Old Keedick lectures, reprints of Connecticut Educ., Amy Loveman)
······Document Cases 330-333
10. Mayor's Task Force on Air Pollution
······Document Cases 334-336
11. Transcripts used for Present Tense
······Document Case 337
12. Editorials
······Document Cases 338-344
13. Present Tense - Encore - Project X
······Document Cases 345-351
14. Correspondence
······Document Cazes 352-395
15. Miscellaneous
······Document Cases 395-401
16. Miscellaneous and Correspondence
······Document Cases 402-403
17. Miscellaneous
······Document Case 404
18. Amy Loveman, Neila Danielus materials
······Document Case 405
19. Miscellaneous
······Document Cases 406-412 (407-HPCA, 410-UWF, 412-USIA)
20. McCall's
······Document Cases 413-414
21. Dec. 1965 Itinerary - Philippines, McCalls
······Document Case 415
22. McCall's
······Document Cases 416-417
23. Miscellaneous
······Document Cases 418-429 (419-SANE, 420 - UWF)
24. Correspondence - 1967, 1968, 1969, 1970
······Document Cases 430-493 (1968-Family of Man)
25. UWF/WAWF - 1966
······Document Cases 495-500
26. National Programming Council: Biographies
······Document Cases 501-504
27. National Programming Council: Meeting materials
······Document Cases 505-509
28. National Programming Council; Accounting Information and Newsclips
······Document Cases 510-515
29. Public TV
······Document Cases 516-521
30. National Programming Council: Projects
······Document Cases 522-524
31. National Programming Council: Membership Information
······Document Cases 525-530
32. Miscellaneous and Correspondence
······Document Cases 531-532
33. Miscellaneous, Correspondence, Dartmouth VI
······Document Cases 533-536
34. Miscellaneous
······Document Case 537 (Lester Pearson, Who Speaks for Man? Film script)
35. Miscellaneous and Correspondence
······Document Cases 538-555 (Hiroshima Maidens, Moral Adoptions, Hiroshima-Nagasaki exhibit)
Related Material
World citizen [oral history transcript] / Norman Cousins, interviewee. UCLA Oral History Department interview, 1992. Available at Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
General note
The following online container list has not yet been edited.
Periodical editors -- United States -- Archives.; Psychoneuroimmunology.; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Archives.; International relations.; Political activists -- Archives.; Cousins, Norman--Archives.; Saturday review.; University of California, Los Angeles--Faculty -- Archives
- Volume 1
  - Document Case #1 Material of The Office of War Information
    - Section 1 The Arts.
      - 1. Clip. Unbound pamphlets, loose paper
        - The Arts in the United States by Ishbel Ross, S-2231 (Box 301)
          Scope and Contents note
          x. Her resume. Table of Contents.
          y. Captions of the pictures.
          Contents.
          1. Music in America.
          (2. Folk Music in America) *missing
          3. Folk Festivals.
          4. American Art.
          5. American Architecture.
          6. U. S. Sculpture and Museums.
          (7. The Commercial Theatre)
          (8. The Community Theatre)
          9. The American Radio.
          10. Motion Pictures.
          General note
          See folder 4 for complete copy.
        - The War's Effect upon the American Theatre. Part II. by John Cassner. (Box 301)
        - The Culturel Growth of the United States since 1900. by Stanley Williams., S-2860 (Box 301)
          Serial article, three parts
        - Trends in American Architecture: by Wm. Wilson Wurster., 1940-1945. April, 1945.; S-7667 (Box 301)
      - 2. Folder. Dance., Unbound pamplets, loose paper.
        - Heidi Schoon, Dancer, Operates U.S. Ceramics Plant., Sept, 1944.; S-6215 (Box 301)
        - English Choreographer 0utstanding in U.S. Ballet. (d.c. Anthony Tudor), July, 1944.; S-5691 (Box 301)
        - English Dancer in U.S. Champions Ballet for All. (d.c.Anton Dolin), July, 1944.; S-5692 (Box 301)
        - U.S. Furniture of Modern Design., Oct, 1944.; S-5984 (Box 301)
        - Art and Archaelogy Newsletter., Oct, 1944.; S-6613 (Box 301)
          See folder 4 of this section.
      - 3. Folder. Literature.
        - Literary Newsletter (editorial, Sat. Rev.) by Wm. Rose Beset. (patriotica ...), April, 1945.; S_7606 (Box 301)
        - Art and Archaelogy Newsletter. by Steph S. Luce & Millard Meiss., Sept 1944.; S-6230 (Box 301)
        - Workshop in Intercultural Education., Sept 1944.; S-6125 (Box 301)
        - The Amer. Acad. of Arts and Sciences, (anniversary), April 1945.; S-7638 (Box 301)
        - Islamic Art Shown in the United States., Dec 1944.; S-7053 (Box 301)
        - Review of 1944, Science, the Arts, and Education., Jan, 1945.; S-7136 (Box 301)
        - Museum of Modern Arts, "Design for Use" Exhibit., Oct 1944.; S-6517 (Box 301)
        - A Century of Creative Photography., Aug 1944.; S-5912 (Box 301)
        - America House Markets U. S. Hand Crafts., June 1944.; S-5299 (Box 301)
        - The Arts in the United States by Ishbel Ross (complete), S-2231 (Box 301)
        - Fine American Glassware., Oct 1944.; S-6426 (Box 301)
        - U. S Architects Plot Post-war Housing, Part I., S-4554 (Box 301)
        - Prefabricated "Half-Hour" Houses., Sept 1944.; S-6321 (Box 301)
        - Achievements in Modern Architecture in America., Sept 1944.; 5-5293 (Box 301)
        - San Francisco Ballet, Oldest Civic Company in America., June 1944.; S-5329 (Box 301)
        - The Byzantine Institute of Istanbul, Paris and Boston. by Seth T. Gano, secy of the Institute., Nov 1944.; S-6763 (Box 301)
        - U. S. Exports Uncover the Mosaics of Hagia Sophia., June 1944.; S-5365 (Box 301)
        - Pottery of North Carolina, S-2260 (Box 301)
        - Guggenheim Scholarships Benefit the Arts and Sciences., Sept 1944; S-6255 (Box 301)
        - Literary Newsletter (Temper of the century... ) by Amy Loverlian., April, 1945; S-7708 (Box 301)
        - Literary Newsletter (New publishing houses...) by Norman Cousins., March, 1945; S-7538 (Box 301)
        - Literary Newsletter (Amer. Humour...) by Henr Seidel Canby., 13 March, 1945; S-7476 (Box 301)
        - Literary Newsletter (Publisher's New Year....) by Norman Cousins., Febr, 1945; S-7260 (Box 301)
        - Profile: Robert Frost, Amer. Poet., 21 July 1944.; S-5772 (Box 301)
        - Wm Saroyan. A 'Living Legend' OWI, June 1944.; S-5420 (Box 301)
        - The Pilgrimage of Ernest Hemingway., July, 1944.; S-5475 (Box 301)
        - Chas F. Lummis-----A Literary Biography., S-3737 (Box 301)
        - John Steinbeck. Literary Reporter., S-3474 (Box 301)
        - U. S. Newspaperman a Leading Post. (d.r. Clifford J. Laube.), S-3973 (Box 301)
        - The Cultural Growth of the United States since 1900. by Stanley Williams. *2nd copy, S-2860 (Box 301)
        - Profile: Sinclair Lewis, U. S. Author., 25 Jan 1944.; S-4153 (Box 301)
      - 4. Folder. Misc.
        - Philatelic Review, by Ernest H. Kehr, Stamp Ed. N. Y. Her-Trib. OWI, April, 1945.; S-7586 (Box 301)
        - Art and Archaeology Newsletter #7. by Steph S. Luce & Millard Meiss OWI, April, 1945.; S-7562 (Box 301)
        - The Reconstruction of Education by I. N. Kandel, April, 1945.; S-7670 (Box 301)
        - Art and Archaeology, Newsletter #5. by Steph S. Luce & Millard Meiss., March, 1945.; S-7436 (Box 301)
        - Art and Archaeology Newsletter. by Steph S. Luce & Millard Meiss., 15 Jan 1945.; S-7246 (Box 301)
        - Art and Archaeology Newsletter #3. by Steph. S. Luce & Millard Meiss., JAN, 1945.; S-7084 (Box 301)
        - Philatelic Newsletter by Ernest A. Kehr, July, 1944.; S-5616 (Box 301)
        - Inter-American Art by David E. Finley., S-4881 (Box 301)
      - 5. Folder. Motion Pictures (Radio &).
        - Library of Old Film Pictures Contains Collectors' Items., June 1945.; S-7838 (Box 301)
        - Film Actor Holds U.S. Democratic Office. (Albert Dekker), Febr 1945.; S-7331 (Box 301)
        - French Film Star Visits United States. (Pierre Blanchar), Febr 1945.; S-7289 (Box 301)
        - New Film Star Climbed to Success in One Picture. (Lauren Bacall), Febr 1945.; S-7291 (Box 301)
        - New Uses For Radio in the United States., Febr 1945.; S-7378 (Box 301)
        - Danny Kaye an Outstanding Comedian of the Screen., Febr 1945.; S-7371 (Box 301)
        - New Film Reflects U.S. Wartime Spirit., Febr 1945.; S-7290 (Box 301)
        - U.S. Radio used as Education Aid., Jan 1945.; S-7248 (Box 301)
        - Young U. S. Composer Enters Cinema Field., Jan 1945.; S-7179 (Box 301)
        - "The Sullivans"---American War Heroes., Dec 1944.; S-6785 (Box 301)
        - Helen Hayes, "The Mighty Atom", Dec. 1944.; S-7005 (Box 301)
        - Famed Novel Filmed in United States. (Richard Llewellyn: "None but the Lonely Heart"), Jan 1945.; S-7178 (Box 301)
        - Paul Muni to play Alfred Nobel on Screen., Jan 1945.; S-7180 (Box 301)
        - Popular Film Star Returns from Philipine Battle., Jan 1945.; S-7177 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Guild to Train Young Actors., Jan 1945.; S-7225 (Box 301)
        - Film of "Grand National" Popular in United States., Jan. 1945.; S-7222 (Box 301)
        - Ethel Barrymore, Stage Star at 65., Jan. 1945.; S-6982 (Box 301)
        - Post-War Schoo1 Courses in Motion Pictures., Dec. 1944; S-6912 (Box 301)
        - Hour a Television Studio Operates., Dec 1944.; S-6905 (Box 301)
        - French. Italian and Spanish "Dubbed" into Hollywood Film., Dec. 1944.; S-6985 (Box 301)
        - American and Russian Film developments., Dec, 1944; S-6924 (Box 301)
        - America's Pictorial Record., Oct 1944.; S-6741 (Box 301)
        - "Winged Victory" depicts Drama of U. S. Air Forces., Dec 1944.; S-6986 (Box 301)
        - Teurneur, Film Director, Merges U. S. and French Techniques., Dec 1944.; S-7011 (Box 301)
        - The Walt Disney Studios---Home of Mickey Mouse., Nov 1944.; S-6823 (Box 301)
        - The American Soldier's Favorite Entertainer. (Dinah Shore), Nov 1944.; S-6770 (Box 301)
        - Robert Montgomery's War Career., Sept 1944.; S-6277 (Box 301)
        - Andre Girard's "Stations cf the Cross"., Dec 1944.; S-6975 (Box 301)
        - Art and Archaeology Newsletter #3. Steph. S. Luce and Millard Meiss., 8 Dec 1944.; S-6884 (Box 301)
        - Michele Morgan finds "One World" Ideas at Work., Dec 1944; S-6925 (Box 301)
        - America's Radio Voice., October, 1944; S-6641 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., 10. Nov 1944; S-6683 (Box 301)
        - Jennifer Jones, Star of Hollvwood's "Song of Bernadette"., S-5148 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., 2 Oct 1944; S-6326 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., 11 April 1944.; S-4707 (Box 301)
        - Humphrey Bogart. Blunt and Outspoken Film Star., Nov 1944.; S-6684 (Box 301)
        - Carole Landis, Hollywood Film Star in Pacific War Theatre., Oct 1944.; S-6589 (Box 301)
        - Paris-born TJ. S. Film Player plans to Return to France. (d.c. Andrea King), Oct 1944.; S-6557 (Box 301)
        - Barrier Finally Plays an American Role., 6 Oct 1944.; S-6406 (Box 301)
        - Manjou, Screen Star Entertained Soldiers Overseas., Oct 1944.; S-6389 (Box 301)
        - James Newcombe, Hollywood Film Editor., Oct 1944; S-6405 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., 11 Sept 1944; S-6207 (Box 301)
        - U. S. Film Star of Spanish Descent., Sept 1944; S-6282 (Box 301)
        - Ann Sheridan Reports on Far-East Tour., 15 Sept 1944; S-6414 (Box 301)
        - Ann Richards, Australian-born Film Star., S-6411 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Script Girl Holds an Important Job., Sept 1944; S-6284 (Box 301)
        - Arc Lamps Flood Film Sets with Brilliant Light., Sept 1944; S-6137 (Box 301)
        - Maria Palmer, New Film Actress., Sept 1944; S-6138 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., Sept 14, 1944; S-6285 (Box 301)
        - Artists Work as Film Directors., Sept 1944; S-6209 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter, Sept 8, 1944.; S-6139 (Box 301)
        - George Korvin. European-born. U.S. Film Star., Sept 1944; S-6063 (Box 301)
        - Alfred Tbarra, Versatile U. S. Artist., Sept 1944; S-6136 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood's Stunt Men Do Dangerous Work for Stars., Sept 1944; S-6090 (Box 301)
        - Film Tells of Impact of War on Amer. Family., Aug 1941; S-6121 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter, Aug 1944.; S-5789 (Box 301)
        - "Soldiers in Greasepaint" Entertain United Nations Troops., Aug 1944; S-5872 (Box 301)
        - "Soldiers in Greasepaint" Lead Home-front Drives., 2 Aug 1944? ); S-5766 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Nswsletter., 31 Aug 1944; S-6061 (Box 301)
        - Charles Boyer, Film Star, Busy with War Work., Aug 1944; S-5966 (Box 301)
        - Claudette Colbert, French-born Amer. Film Star., Aug 1944; S-5901 (Box 301)
        - Merle Oberon, British-born Hollywood Film Star., Aug 1944; S-5937 (Box 301)
        - Victor Francen, Belgian-born Actor, in Hollywood., Aug 1944; S-5965 (Box 301)
        - Explosives Experts devise Hollywood Battle-scene Blasts., Aug 1944; S-5831 (Box 301)
        - Gracie Fields, English Star in Hollywood., Aug 1944; S-5817 (Box 301)
        - Carts Grant to Star in Hollywood's "None but the Lonely Heart"., Aug 1944; S-5816 (Box 301)
        - Peter Godfrey, English-born Hollywood Director., Aug 1944; S-5819 (Box 301)
        - Son of Korean Patriot is U. S. Film Actor., July 1944; S-5725 (Box 301)
        - Film Dog's Earnings Help Blinded War Veterans., July 1944; S-5727 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter, 4 July 1944; S-5696 (Box 301)
        - Rouben Mamoulian, Popular Film Director., July 1944; S-5641 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Entertainers Expect Philippine Assignments., July 1944; S-5555 (Box 301)
        - Bette Davis tells of Her Work., July 1944; S-5661 (Box 301)
        - The Motion Picture Academy's Activities during 1944 by Walter Wanger, president, Acad. Mot. Fict. Arts & Sc., Mar. 1945.; S-7641 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Studios Maintain Schools for Child Actors., March 1945.; S-7546 (Box 301)
        - America's Amateur Film Makers, April 1945; S-7507 (Box 301)
        - Sound Technique Overcomes "Dead" Spots in Cinema Houses., March 1945; S-7506 (Box 301)
        - Screen Star returns from China Burrs India Tour. (Pat O'Brien), Febr 1945; S-7377 (Box 301)
        - British Hospital Setting For Broadway Play., Oct 1944; S-6439 (Box 301)
        - U.S. Film Star Entertains Troops in Alaska. (Ingrid Bergman), S-4366 (Box 301)
        - New Uses for Radio in the United States., Febr 1945.; S-7378 (Box 301)
        - The Radio Corporation of America Research Laboratory., March 1945; S-7491 (Box 301)
      - 6. Motion Pictures Folder.
        Note in folder: Motion Pictures to Aug. 20/44 - Cousins' file
        - The Complex Job of Hollywood Costume Designers., S-4185 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter, 12 July 1944.; S-5556 (Box 301)
        - Ray Milland, Welsh-born Film Star., June 1944.; S-5259 (Box 301)
        - How Film Stars Lesrn their Lines., July 1944.; S-5508 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood's Youngest Top-flight Director is of Russian Descent. (Edw. Dmytryk), June 1944; S-5471 (Box 301)
        - Jack Benny, U. S. Film and Radio Star, Entertaining Troops., June 1941; S-5330 (Box 301)
        - Authentic Russian Scenes Recreated in U.S. Film., June 1944.; S-5328 (Box 301)
        - Maureen O'Hara Portrays Varied Screen Types., S-3720 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter, 4 Jan 1944.; S-3770 (Box 301)
        - Fan Mail Advice Heeded in Hollywood., June 1944.; S-5422 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter, June 1944.; S-5423 (Box 301)
        - Joseph Calleia, Nollvwood Film Player,, Native of Malta., June 1944.; S-5324 (Box 301)
        - Motion Picture Hazards Restful for Italian-born Actor. (Geo. Dolenz), May 1944; S-5232 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter, June 1944; S-5244 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Cameramen Working on All War Fronts., June 1944.; S-5233 (Box 301)
        - European Stars in Hollywood Continue Battle against Fascism., S-5051 (Box 301)
        - LeRoy Prinz, Hollywood Dance Director., June 1944; S-5326 (Box 301)
        - Sydney Greenstreet U.S. Film Villain, born in England., June 1944.; S-5327 (Box 301)
        - Liorel Barrymore, Composer. *2nd copy, S-5149 (Box 301)
        - Betty Grable, "Pin-up" Champion., June 1944.; S-5199 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., 19 May 1944.; S-5023 (Box 301)
        - U. S. Screen Idol Returns to Films. (Francis Y. Bushman), S-5000 (Box 301)
        - Los Angeles Honours United Nations., May 1944; S-5198 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Honours George Pal, Hungarian-born Producer., S-5069 (Box 301)
        - U.S. Firms send Medicines to Many Parts of World., June 1944.; S-5276 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Films Reflect Public Desire for Fine Literature., S-5118 (Box 301)
        - Paulette Goddard--"Kiss Precious Cargo"., S-5052 (Box 301)
        - Film Star Paulette Goddard entertains U. S. Troops in India and China., S-4923 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., 6 May 1944.; S-4929 (Box 301)
        - Hedy Lamarr. Film Beauty and U.S. Canteen Hostess., S-4921 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., 18 April 1944; S-4761 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., 8 April 1944; S-4610 (Box 301)
        - American Cinema Looks back over First 50 Years., S-4714 (Box 301)
        - Hungarian Motion-Picture Director Stresses Music. By Joseph Pasternak., S-4444. (Box 301)
        - The Army studies Films., S-4563 (Box 301)
        - Seven Sons of Lebanon Operate Motion-Picture Chain., S-4626 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., S-4431 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., S-4104 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood supports League for War-workers and Troops., S-4225 (Box 301)
        - Yugoslav Film-expert Perfects Montage Technique., S-4322 (Box 301)
        - Wounded U.S. War Heroes fight again, but for Films., S-4334 (Box 301)
        - U. S. Soliers enjoy Varied Motion-picture Fare., S-4257 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., S-4227 (Box 301)
        - U. S. Motion-picture Ingenuity Creates Wartime Substitutes, S-4347 (Box 301)
        - The Future of Motion-Pictures in China., S-4267 (Box 301)
        - America's Box-office Mr. Leaders., S-4075 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Actor of Yugoslav Descent Works for Victory., S-4200 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Property Men Specialise in Old Furnishings., S-4094 (Box 301)
        - U.S. Screen Star made Acting Debut in School Pageant. (Don Ameche), S-4183 (Box 301)
        - Joseph Calleia: U.S. Actor. with International Background, S-3968 (Box 301)
        - Actor of Irish Descent Portrays Many Nationalities. (J. Carroll Naish), S-4022 (Box 301)
        - Master Plasterer of Hollywood., S-4073 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Experts Achieve Miracles in make-up., S-4027 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., S-4093 (Box 301)
        - Youthful Actors Go to School on Hollywood Lots., S-3776 (Box 301)
        - Hungarian-born Paul Lukas a Star of U. S. Stage and Screen., S-3819 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Is 'Special Effects'., S-3707 (Box 301)
        - Utmost Skill Required of Hollywood Stuntmen., S-3733 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., 18 Nov 1943.; S-3430 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter., 11 Dec 1943; S-3639 (Box 301)
        - Turhan Bev's Success in Hollywood Films., S-3583 (Box 301)
        - Film Premieres in Hollywood., S-3335 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood Newsletter, 3 Nov 1943; S-3344 (Box 301)
        - Hollywood's Role in War Photography. by Vera Caspary., S-3100 (Box 301)
      - 7. Music. FOLDER.
        - A Brief Resumé of Musical Activity in Southern California (1939-1945) by Lawrence Morton, May 1945.; S-7746 (Box 301)
        - Music in the U.S. Pacific Northwest. by George Frederick McKay, May 1945.; S-7742 (Box 301)
        - Musical Education in the United States. by R. D. Welch, March 1945; S-7480 (Box 301)
        - The Metropolitan Opera on Tour. March 1945, S-7488 (Box 301)
        - Opera in the United States during the War. by Douglas Moore, Febr 1945; S-7334 (Box 301)
        - Rare Cvmbals Made from Middle East Formula. (d.r. Avedis Zildjian, coppersmith), Dec 1944; S-6978 (Box 301)
        - World Music Organisation Proposed., Jan 1945; S-7091 (Box 301)
        - America's Industrial Museums., Dec 1944; S-6935 (Box 301)
        - America's Appreciation of Tchaikovsky., April 1945; S-7590 (Box 301)
        - Music in San Francisco. by Alfred Frankenstein., April 1945.; 8-7600 (Box 301)
        - Music in American Schools., Dec 1944; S-6981 (Box 301)
        - America's Musician's Congress., Nov 1944.; S-6756 (Box 301)
        - Oldest U.S. Settlement Music School has 1200 Pupils., Oct 1944.; S-6649 (Box 301)
        - English-born Engineer Photographs Music in Colour., Oct 1944.; S-6553 (Box 301)
        - Carrillons new Part of American Scene., Sept 1944.; S-5620 (Box 301)
        - Trend of American Music. by Gian-carlo Menotti., Oct 1944.; S-6307 (Box 301)